Andromeda is a science fiction film directed by Brett Bentman.
A young man must travel to the furthest reaches of the
universe to find his long lost father.
Aiden Crawford, played by Tim Llewellyn.
Mr. Will Crawford, played by Paul T. Taylor.
Joseph Sharp, played by Tom Zembrod.
Mrs. Will Crawford, played by Tiffany McDonald.
Robert McGrady, played by Michael Dooley.
Rebecca, played by Genine Ware.
The Andromeda Strain is a 1971 American science fiction thriller film produced and directed by Robert
Wise, based on Michael Crichton's 1969 novel of the same name and adapted by Nelson Gidding.
The film stars Arthur Hill, James Olson, Kate Reid, and David Wayne as a team of
scientists who investigate a deadly organism of extraterrestrial origin.
The film follows the book closely with only a few exceptions.
The special effects were designed by Douglas Trumbull, and are notable
for their use of advanced computerized photography.
Real laboratory scenes using a spectrograph were shot at Caltech.
Composer Gil Mellé recorded actual lab sounds for the film at the Jet Propulsion
Laboratory (JPL) for authenticity while doing research for the film score.
Microbiologist Abigail A.
Salyers noted that the film raised real concerns with the larger
public about the risks of interplanetary contamination.
Environmental scientist Michael Paul Meltzer referred to the larger story as a "touchstone for planetary
protection specialists in discussing matters of back contamination and the dangers that they present".
The tone is thought_provoking.